In the 20th century.
if you wanted to know your neighbors.
you move to the suburbs.
If you wanted to become an addict. you move to New York.
Now. everything's upside down.
the junkies are in the burbs.
And the building next door is a fucking kickball league.
It was art against commerce and commerce won.
The kids think the only place
to find art is in the gallery.
And the only place to find romance
is to confessing your love in the rain.
Like in the movies.
But it's messier than that. There's always mess.
It's safe here now. but there's still urban decay.
It's just. migrated to the dinner parties
of the upper Westside.
The best lack all conviction while the worst
are filled with passionate intensity.
Yeats said that but so did Lou Reed
Quoting him live at the Bottom Line.
Lou Reed's gone and so is the Bottom Line.
It's probably a Soul Cycle. only soul the city has left.
Everyone's pretending it's all okay. But that's a lie.
Something's missing and we all feel it.
Including Thomas Webb. he thought he had the answer.
And her name was Mimi.
Nineteen seventy-six. The city
was dirty. crime-ridden. and broke.
It was the center of the creative universe.
New York's lost its soul.
Most favorite neighborhood at the moment is Philadelphia.
- I like that.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. where'd you lift that from?
- I didn't. it's mine.
Well. it's good.
So. will you come with me tonight?
No. your mum's last dinner party made me feel invisible.
I know. but. we're invisible together.
- If you don't like it. then you don't go.
- I have to go.
My mother's unstable. throwing dinner parties
- is how she medicates.
- Yeah. what about the lithium and Xanax?
Not to mention. the nicotine and shiraz.
Semantics.
- I have to tell you something.
- Yeah?
Yeah. I...
- Might be going to Zagreb.
- Where?
Zagreb. it's in Croatia.
So. Helmut Graph. he runs a workshop there.
And I found out that I can transfer my credits to NYU.
That's... That's... terrible.
Why?
No. why is that terrible?
Because you're the only thing in my life I'm settled on.
Thomas. what do you think is happening?
Between me and you. what do you think this is?
- August 8th. I think August 8th was real.
- It was amazing.
But it was just one night.
I mean Nick was playing L.A.. I was vulnerable.
We were both on molly. I thought I was a pirate.
It was just one night.
Well. I'm crazy about you.
- And I'm crazy about you but...
- But. don't say as friends.
- Why? Why is that so bad?
- Because pretty girls like to recruit
their rejections and call them friends.
Wow.
For Mimi. Thomas was like the new New York.
No danger. no deliverance.
It made him nurturing and too boring to fall in love with.
Mimi felt Thomas was a boy without mystery.
Thomas agreed.
But all that was about to change.
- Anything worth opening?
- Just bills and junk.
W.F.. W.F. Gerald I just moved into 2B.
Thomas Webb.
- Why so troubled. Thomas?
- Excuse me.
I know that color of stress.
It's much brighter than job issues.
more subdued than possible disease.
- Sorry. I'm being rude.
- No. I mean...
I'm having a bad day.
What's her name?
- It's Mimi.
- Mimi.
Derived from Wilhelmina. It means resolute protector.
There you go.
What a... what is it you like about this Mimi?
You're a psychiatrist?
- No.
- You ask psychiatrist questions.
Maybe I can help.
Maybe I can help you to get Mimi to sleep with you.
How do you know. she hasn't already?
It was nice meeting you.
Well. why don't you let a new neighbor help you out?
What do you like about Mimi?
I'm in 2B.
Where'd you meet her?
There's this book store called The Pale Fire.
- It's named after John Shade...
- John Shade's 999 line poem.
Nabokov.
Right. well.
They sold rare. vintage books in there.
And I'm into that. Just reading off the beaten back and...
Mimi works there. she gave me the greatest recommendations.
You know.
She's putting herself through NYU's writing program.
- She reads a book a week.
- She's polishing her brain.
Beautiful?
Incredibly beautiful.
Like she's direct from God. you know.
On second generation. if that makes sense.
Don't believe sense.
You know we get each other.
Problem. was...
Is. that she has this boyfriend.
Nick. he's in that...
band. Fahrenheit 185.
The exact temperature it takes to cook heroin.
Properly.
Let's see what we got.
Here we go.
Anyways. so. Nick goes on tour.
Mimi's now available and we're hanging out more.
We end up spending...
a magical night together.
August 8th. and then...
Nothing. All goes platonic.
How old is Mimi?
She's. 22. She just turned 22.
She's young. Well...
she's at an age. where defense mechanisms are very strong.
Despite her outer veneer. she's ruled by fear.
Like so many of us at that time.
I know... what you need to do.
Just make her afraid of something more
than being with you. in that way.
Which is?
Not being with you.
But how?
How I am supposed to do that?
Let life take over.
find a window and pounce.
That's it? That's you sage-ably advice?
- Can I have my money back. please?
- Thomas.
- Is it Thomas or Tom?
- It's Thomas.
- Not Tommy?
- No. never.
Thomas. you're not giving life enough credit.
The unpredictable forces of humanity...
My life is not unpredictable.
my life is conventional my life is boring.
No. it's as random as it is deliberate.
It's funny as it is tragic.
Yours is no exception. I gotta piss.
Dinner parties were Judith's safety blanket.
A table full of artists took her mind of her herself.
The swirl of distractions. seating plans. gossip. food.
anything to keep away the dread.
They were the perfect antidote to her childhood dinners.
The silences. the drunken outbursts.
Artists came to New York from all over.
and she always took them in.
Clinging to the illusion of an open happy family.
Do you miss getting mugged on Central Park West...
- Exactly. exactly.
- No. but I do miss.
the second avenue deli. I miss the Lenox Lounge.
I mean do you know. what are in those iconic places now.
Urban Outfitters. a Starbucks.
There's a John Varvatos where CBGB's use to be.
- New York's lost its soul.
- Exactly!
What was that Thomas?
Well. I was just agreeing with David
that New York has lost its soul.
Since he returned from 3 months in Peru.
he's decided to hate where he's from.
No. it's true.
New York's most vibrant neighborhood
at the moment is Philadelphia.
That's very funny. Thomas.
So. Ethan. I heard you've commissioned Nick Bilton
to write the biography on Evan Dereif.
Our mandate. it came to us very simple.
Bios on any haircut under 40.
as long as they're still within their fifteen minutes.
Self-help. political rants.
- Nobody reads fiction anymore.
- Anyone's a writer...
- so cynical. Ethan Webb.
- I know...
If I were a writer.
we'd be having this conversation
in a two bedroom in Bushwick.
Bushwick is expensive now.
I'm serious. I'm really serious.
I mean. most novelists these days.
they don't own enough money to support themselves.
No matter how talented they are.
That's why if Thomas came to me with a desire to be writer.
I'd talk him out of it.
So. you're still tutoring. right?
Yeah. just for some extra cash.
- He could be a Spanish teacher.
- Yes. he actually could.
- I don't know if I could be a Spanish...
- If you went back to collage for a year.
For some reason he refuses to do it.
He lives on the lower east side without any direction.
Only thing missing is an opium habit.
What about doing a smartphone application?
This man moved in across the hall from me.
I don't what he does. or who he is but.
Seems familiar to me.
He's my new friend.
Yeah.
- He asked about you.
- Me? He knows me.
What's my father doing here?
Who's he with?
I don't know.
She's beautiful.
Do you have any idea what this is gonna do to my mother?
This doesn't mean your father loves you any less.
I'm sorry. that was bad enough.
I know like dispensing therapy
from an after-school specialist...
He doesn't care about me to begin with I know that.
This... this is about my mother.
Yeah. but. it's their problem.
- You have your own problems.
- Like what?
Actually don't. don't answer that. Not now.
Thomas. look at me.
Look. your parents.
their world.
is nothing like ours.
I mean maybe it's their generation or...
I don't know this island.
But you're kind.
And you're real.
Don't do that.
Mimi. look. you're young.
and your defense mechanism is strong.
but I think that you want this.
- I think that you're confused right now.
- No Mimi. I'm angry right now.
I'm angry.
Did you see that woman? Did you see how beautiful she was?
I could never get a woman like that.
My father with his publishing house.
his good looks. and it's cheating...
fucking hair.
So what. you're gonna use
your father's affairs as a confirmation
of your own inadequacies?
No. I mean.
I have you for that.
So. you call my office.
you say you wanna have lunch. you never wanna have lunch.
I figured you had a big surprise.
- Maybe you figured out your life.
- No.
Definitely haven't figured out my life.
- I wanted to speak to you about...
- Ethan.
- Good to see you.
- Of course anytime.
- I actually enjoyed the show.
- It was good. wasn't it?
- It was great.
- Great. say hi to Judith.
I will indeed.
I want you to move from the lower east side.
Why do you insist on living in the
farthest corner of Manhattan away from us?
I think it's intentional.
I think it's almost hurtful.
Look.
I'm not asking for me. I'm asking for your mother.
She wants you closer to home.
How is mom?
Better.
I guess.
- Can't get her to quit smoking.
- She is fragile.
Anything. even the smallest thing could. create another.
incident.
I'll pay the difference in rent.
Will you think about it?
- Dad.
- Also. I setup an appointment
with a career counselor for you.
My office will email you the info.
Dad. I know you. I know...
You know I'm what. Thomas?
I know you're just trying to help.
Don't blow it up. okay?
I had to call in a favor for her to see you.
she actually has a waiting list.
- Are you gonna confront your father?
- No. trouble talking to him.
Why?
I don't think. he likes me that much.
What the...
What exactly is wrong with your mother?
I don't know. she's depressed. Bipolar.
She's depressive bipolar.
She came from a broken home. so.
Whenever anything threatens our perfect family.
she. completely unravels.
Can't tell her. she'd be destroyed.
Why don't you furnished this place?
I live in Brooklyn.
- You have two apartments?
- I'm rich.
I'm a fucking duke.
Maybe he's. been faithful all these years.
Maybe she came on to him.
I've seen her. she's irresistible.
- I mean...
- Alright. stop.
- What do you want?
- Well. my father stop seeing this woman.
No. no. no. in life?
You know. in your life.
You want more money? You want more respect?
What is that you want?
Think about it. really think about it.
- I wanna be better.
- Better?
In what?
I don't know.
In the 80's. Ethan was intoxicated by literary New York.
But when he accepted that he lacked
the talent to create a fictional family.
he thought. at least he could create a real one.
Young Thomas loved to write.
Ethan ignored this.
Wary of nurturing a life of rejections and evictions.
And Thomas learned to keep his stories to himself.
The intensity of Judith's bond with her son.
left Ethan feeling like a stranger in his own home.
He sought refuge in work.
until publishing began its slow decline.
Then came Johanna.
You know. private detectives get paid by the hour.
To just. just wait.
To do exactly what we're doing right now.
What is the difficulty in a stakeout?
I really gotta go to class.
No. just wait. all right? He's gonna be out in a minute.
I have to see if he's gonna meet her again.
Please.
Just wait.
Okay.
My God. that's her.
The other woman.
I'll call you later.
- Wait. aren't we waiting for your dad.
- I'll call you later.
What is it exactly that you wanna accomplish?
I wanna meet her.
I wanna tell her to stop seeing my father.
- She could kill my mother.
- So. do it.
I haven't built up the courage yet.
- So you stalk her.
- I shouldn't be dealing with this at all.
I should be on a beach.
with Mimi.
Naked.
In Croatia.
We should be together. together.
Should is a dangerous word.
I'm serious. man.
If it wasn't for my mother. I wouldn't be here.
I don't buy it.
You don't buy what?
I don't buy that this is just about your mother's health.
You have something more here.
Something more what?
Provocative.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me.
- Yes.
- You don't know who I am.
- Yes. I do.
- You do?
- You're the boy who follows me.
- Yeah. well. I have a good reason.
- You're also Ethan's son.
He keeps a picture of you on his desk.
Are you hungry. Thomas?
Following someone in this city got to be very difficult.
It's so easy to be anonymous here.
Why didn't you say anything when I was following you?
Why didn't you say anything?
Because I didn't know what I was gonna do.
- And do you now?
- Yes.
Is it good?
- Johanna.
- Johanna?
- I'm Johanna.
- Okay. Johanna.
How long have you been fucking my father?
Okay. is that kind of vulgarity entirely necessary?
What kind of vulgarity would you prefer?
A little bit over a year.
Why are you even seeing him? He's married.
He is married.
- Do you work with him?
- Sometimes.
I'm a freelance editor. so.
I work for all the houses.
Do you love him?
Define love. Thomas.
Do you think you're gonna marry him?
Is that the plan. you think you're
gonna steal him away from my mother?
How do you know your mother isn't giving him to me?
- What's that supposed to mean?
- I mean. people do things all the time
without realizing.
Your mother may be giving me Ethan
without comprehending it.
You're doing something right now. without realizing it.
Yeah. what I'm doing?
- You're trying to make love to me.
- I'm trying to make love to...
I'm trying to make love to you?
You just don't realize it.
Andy Warhol was a close personal friend
and he gave us that piece as a gift.
And now this God damn committee.
- Is going to take all that away.
- Mom. it doesn't really matter.
These people. these nonentities in Chelsea
their trying to steal my past.
- they're trying to erase my memories.
- Mom!
We're gonna find the photo.
Look at this mess.
I need a cigarette.
But your father has declared
I'm no longer allowed to smoke in the house. so...
I'll stay here and keep searching.
Thomas. I wanna smoke and talk to you at the same time.
- It makes the cigarette better.
- Okay.
Thank you.
It's just this perpetual cycle
of expectations and disappointments.
You know. the farthest distance in the world.
is between how it is and how you thought it was gonna be.
Don't forget that.
I won't.
You're my light. Thomas.
You know.
I don't know what I'd do without you.
It's this Klonopin.
- It makes me so fucking emotional.
- You're fine.
Why don't you stop seeing my father?
Hello. Thomas.
You're a very beautiful woman.
you can get any man you want in this city.
Can I get you?
What?
You said I can get any man in this city. so I'm asking.
Can I get you?
Which actually begs another question really.
Are you a man?
My mother's in a fragile state.
- This affair could put her over the top.
- How am I responsible for your mother...
- Because you're fucking my father.
- Crudeness doesn't make one a man.
- Stop seeing him.
- Nor do demands.
I'm not trying to be a man.
I'm not trying to make love to you.
I'm trying to save my mother.
You're getting closer.
Johanna wasn't raised by writers.
She was raised by bankers.
But the lingua franca both is fiction.
When Ethan floated the idea of leaving his wife.
she assumed it was just talk.
But to her surprise. his suggestion unbalanced her.
Instead of feeling flattered she felt suddenly. needy.
Thomas's attention was the perfect remedy
to her rattled confidence.
The visions of Johanna.
She's not like anyone I've ever met.
She said I was trying to make love to her.
Well. were you?
No. I wanted her to stop seeing my father.
Isn't that between you and your father.
Why would you wanna make contact with her?
She's an outsider to what seems to me to be a family issue.
Eat that.
It's good.
- What was it?
- You don't wanna know.
So what are you saying?
- I like dealing with her?
- That's precisely what I'm saying.
And that I wanna make love to her?
- Would you like to make love to her?
- No!
What kind of question is that? Sick!
- How is that sick?
- It's sick.
She's a beautiful woman.
- So?
- Her name is Johanna.
She's sleeping with my father.
- Would you like to make love to Johanna?
- Would you give me some credit. please?
- This conversation's perverse.
- Answer the question.
Give me some credit.
Stop drowning yourself in what you think is moral.
Do you wanna fuck Johanna?
Yes.
- I would.
- You said your life was boring.
I couldn't have handled today without you.
You know. I got hit on three times
coming from the bathroom.
I'm pretty sure they're all married.
It's a good thing my father isn't here.
That's not funny.
No.
- The groom is coming.
- It's my ninja.
It's my motherfucking ninja.
- Congratulation. man!
- Thanks. man!
This is Mimi. Howard.
- Nice to meet you.
- Congrats.
Listen! I've been running
through Riverside Park. every day.
Nine miles. murdering sobriety.
I've seen a lot your mother. lately actually.
- My mother?
- Yeah. yeah. I don't know.
she's always on the same bench reading a book.
It's Irwin. Irwin.
You guys gotta meet Irwin Sanders. he's buying the Knicks.
Howard. hoes does it feel being married?
Sex already sucks.
Kidding. kind of.
Condé Nast. took me back actually. so...
Maybe anyway. I can get an interview at some point.
Maybe.
Howard. this is my friend Johanna.
- Hello. congratulations.
- Thank you.
This is Thomas.
- Johanna.
- Mimi.
Hi.
You're being really obvious.
I'm not dating Irwin.
It's none of your business.
I don't have to explain myself to you. but none the less.
He's a very good friend.
- Where's your girlfriend?
- She's not.
She's just a friend.
You shouldn't let her do that to you.
He's 30 years older than you. he's a billionaire.
- I'm not stupid.
- You are quite stupid. Thomas.
And you've got no idea how the world works.
And actually he's not a billionaire anymore.
- You cannot see the path of everything.
- Doesn't really matter.
No. it doesn't.
You look nice.
You look very nice.
In a suit.
I don't really think you're stupid.
Just.
confused.
Young.
Irwin's probably looking for you.
- I'm sure he paid for the whole night.
- Fuck you. really.
Hey.
- So. first of all. hooker comments.
- I know. I'm sorry.
- You actually resorted to hooker comments?
- I'm sorry.
- I apologize.
- Okay.
Second of all. Irwin's gay.
Okay. he loves men.
In fact he loves one man in particular.
A man named Billy Analdi.
who happens to be an incredible art dealer
and one of my closes friends.
So. Irwin doesn't want to come out for business reasons.
which is his prerogative.
and I come to events like this with him.
I'm not a glorified hooker.
he's not a sugar daddy. I'm his beard.
You really don't know how the world works.
You're innocent. Thomas. you're a child.
- I know somethings.
- Yeah?
Like what?
How it went down.
- You. my dad. I know.
- Do you?
Okay Thomas. Mr. Ace Sleuth. I wanna hear it.
You noticed that he liked to come in early.
Really early like. what?
Seven in the morning?
So. you started coming in then. too. isolate and contain.
Told him it was because you don't sleep well.
with the bad dreams. they shake you awake before daylight.
In the mornings. you put on music in your office.
Browns one day. Biggie Smalls the next.
because. you know. you can't be put into a box.
You attack all the senses.
You went a little aggressive on your signature scent.
Strong on the vanilla.
You mention a boyfriend. then complain of a bad date.
you confuse him. you make him wonder.
The sex.
The sex. the sex surprise you both.
And he was just walking you home after dinner.
Well. Jesus. you're not the other woman.
He's not a cheating husband.
No. this isn't something we did.
this is something that happened to us.
But what? Could it be love?
No. Nobody wants to acknowledge that. so soon in the game.
but stars are crossed and people are gonna get hurt. and.
we've done a bad. bad thing. Ethan.
so fuck. it must be right.
And all of it was just bullshit. calculated and manipulated
from that first lie about your bad dreams. 'Cause I'm...
I'm pretty sure that you sleep like a baby.
You are quite a story teller.
- Where have you been?
- Bathroom. drank too much.
I have to interrupt now because.
I have to go home.
I'm Uncle Buster.
Let's get out of here.
- They haven't even cut the cake.
- Fuck the cake. Let's go.
What?
- Why?
- Come on.
Walter's not here because.
- You smell like vanilla.
- He's doing two to five.
It's no secret.
'Cause. you all know. two to five.
for doing the right thing.
For believing in the poetry of the constitution.
I have only a few thoughts.
Drama.
Dramatics of marital romance.
Staying together.
Like the gypsy...
told me the poems.
written in life lines are never guaranteed.
They get busted up.
Its moral begins new poetry.
Another romance that will explode
from time to time.
Poetry of married people. like.
the Aurora Borealis.
Strewn like stars in the sky
and the drama of your lives begins.
Chapter after chapter.
Stories.
Books.
Revolutions.
as I know. will come.
I've seen many. lived through them.
They play in the least expected places. So get ready.
Casey understands Howard. Howard.
knows Casey.
No. No. not yet.
There's always mystery.
You both know that.
You both know it isn't perfect.
Excitement.
Trust.
And struggle.
And the unknown privacies.
That keep us together.
Glue of struggle.
I raise my glass.
Fragile glass who was stumped on and shattered.
And we'll forever be putting back together.
Like the puzzles.
we first worked as children.
Learning to be patient.
Searching for what fits.
So many puzzles.
So many books in this room.
I talk too much.
Let's dance.
So I have to. go to this career counselor.
My father setup the appointment.
Why don't you go into journalism?
You were in the high school newspaper.
It doesn't interest me anymore.
And you won the advertising prize
in college. you could do that.
How do you this about me?
- How do you know all this?
- I know everything.
Everything about you.
Okay. yeah. but can we see?
- President of the debate club.
- Yeah.
Arts editor of the high school newspaper.
Second single on the tennis team.
Very impressive. Thomas.
Your father has all your awards on his desk.
- So awful.
- That's awkward.
For the career counselor.
Alright. here's something you don't know.
And nobody knows.
Okay.
I wanted to write.
I used to write all these things when I was younger.
A bunch of letters from my dog to like
the mail man.
The vet. Eventually I...
came up with a collection of essays called.
"Mary Jane Versus Everything".
Which I was incredibly proud of.
And. you know. I show them to my dad.
What did Ethan say?
Serviceable.
- Ouch.
- Yeah.
Serviceable. that was his exact word.
Nothing special. just serviceable.
He seemed pretty angry after reading them though.
- Well. I wanna read them.
- You do?
- Yeah.
- You can't.
- Why not?
- Because I threw them out.
That's so sad.
That's so sad of an ending.
That's good.
Really?
What word did your father use?
- Serviceable.
- I disagree.
I think you've got talent.
But. your father is a publisher and I'm just some.
strange neighbor. so you're gonna go with serviceable.
- Johanna wanted to read them.
- Right.
- I don't know if I could...
- Those visions of Johanna.
I think about her...
all the time.
Maybe it's love.
I don't know.
Love is hard to determine.
People think they're in love
and it's something completely different.
Infatuation.
The righting of childhood wrongs.
No companionship.
Have you ever been in love?
Yeah. once.
Who was she?
She was this woman I knew.
She was taken by someone else. a dear friend.
We had a profound connection. but she was his girl.
It was a mess.
So what did you do?
I left the scene of the crime.
You ran away?
Well. at the time I called it an adventure.
But hindsight turned it into something else
which is what hindsight inevitably does.
Yeah. I ran away. I'm gonna take this.
- Leave you with your heart on.
- My hard on.
Heart. your heart on.
You know what. maybe.
in hindsight I'll feel guilty
about Johanna. but right now I don't.
It's not cut or dry.
Congratulations. Thomas.
Your world's becoming contextual.
Who the fuck are you?
Hey dad.
What's up?
Sit down.
Is everything alright?
Is mom okay?
Sit down. Thomas.
Is there anything you want to tell me?
No.
No. nothing.
Anything I should know?
No.
Thomas...
You blew off the career counselor.
I told you how hard it was to get that appointment
and then you just don't show up.
- Gone!
- Right. I'm...
- I should have called. Sorry.
- You should have called. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. too.
Come work here.
Work here. You like to read.
I've been conflicted about giving you a job here.
nepotism and all that bullshit. but screw it.
You can start under the junior editors.
You know. learn something.
- No. thank you.
- Why not?
I mean what's wrong with learning the publishing business?
Nothing. It's fine. It's just it's...
Serviceable.
W.F.?
I just wanna get my essays back.
Hey.
Thomas.
I was in your apartment.
You're Julian Stellars.
A nom de plume.
You've had twelve books published.
You don't have much mass appeal.
but you don't seem to mind.
Hard to find a picture of you anywhere.
You're an alcoholic who spends most afternoons drinking
in Brooklyn Inn.
And you're probably the only person
I've met that's actually.
actually been to an opium den.
Have I been googled?
I didn't read it.
The new manuscript.
Well. Thomas. I appreciate that.
So...
You said I had talent.
It was a professional's opinion.
I don't know. man. I...
You've experienced the world. I just live here in New York.
New York is the world.
I haven't done much with my life.
You've had sex with your father's mistress?
I'd say that's something.
Am I the only living boy in New York?
You are.
Hey. I was outside your apartment.
You're not there. I brought the essays.
I wanted to show you.
Did you sleep with her?
With who?
Johanna?
Why would you ask that?
They left the wedding as quickly as we did.
I may be oblivious but I am not stupid.
- Why do you care?
- I just do.
- Why?
- Thomas.
- You jealous?
- No.
- You sure?
- Thomas.
I think you are jealous.
- Did you sleep with her?
- She's my father's mistress.
You think that I would do that?
No.
Thank you.
You're sweet.
You're not like them.
- Like who?
- The city.
I want you to stop seeing him.
No. I'm putting my foot down.
You don't get to tell me what to do. Thomas.
- I don't care if your foot's down or up.
- Why. cause you don't care about anything?
- What?
- You obviously don't
care about anything at all.
So. I'm a nihilist now. am I?
I don't know anything about you.
Where did you grow up?
Brooklyn. Thomas. That's why I have this accent.
Did you play sports?
No.
When did you first have sex?
My God. are we gonna talk about my childhood now?
Yeah. I wanna know you.
Where did you grow up?
I grew up in London.
Which part?
Belsize Park.
Then. Kilburn.
Why the move?
Because Kilburn is so much more real.
What your dad do?
What does your dad do?
He put a gun in his mouth and pulled the trigger.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
Why do you sleep with me?
- Because I like you.
- What do you like about me?
Your innocence.
Were you ever innocent?
I forgot.
Come on? Tell me.
I wanna know about when you were innocent.
- Why?
- Because I like the idea of it.
If you want someone so pure. why are you with me?
Because I care about you.
You care about me?
I don't care for anyone. remember?
But the truth was. she cared about them both.
And that's when she knew. this mess would only get worse.
She had to make a clean break. starting with Ethan.
What she didn't anticipate was.
he'd surrendered too much of his past
to give up on his future.
You think he's in love with her?
He just has to stop.
You and your father...
You suffer from the same disease.
Johanna.
Visions of Johanna. Conquered my mind.
Why are you writing about me?
That's what I do.
I write about people I know and then give them a thin veil.
Why me?
Look. I...
I got the apartment to get out of the house
and write a completely different story.
- It didn't come across.
- Mine did.
But like everything good.
it happened by accident. I met you. now I got 118 pages.
My father's publishing house. they're
throwing an anniversary party tomorrow.
You should come.
No.
You've heard all about these people but you never met them.
Good for the book.
Find a window.
Pounce.
And pounce.
I broke up with Nick.
Did you?
You are supposed to be more excited than that.
Hey.
Thanks for coming.
It's a great party.
Yeah. always is.
That's my mother. Mimi.
She's beautiful.
I told you she was.
I was talking about your mother.
It is amazing. But I can keep...
Sorry. I want you to come meet somebody.
Oh. who are we meeting?
- Meeting my new friend.
- Your new friend?
- Sorry. sorry.
- All right. I will be back.
He was just here.
He was?
Well. maybe meet him later.
There's Dan.
"I look down upon the city from high windows."
It was then that the great buildings...
lose reality and take on their magical powers.
Squares and squares of flame. set and cut into the ether.
"Here's our poetry..."
"For we have pulled down the stars to our will."
- "To our will..."
- Ezra Pound.
Johanna. I'm assuming.
We haven't met. have we?
No. but I know you very well.
And I know that you're having your fun.
And that he's young and easy.
But you'll have me to deal with if he scars.
I don't like strange conversations.
So. I'm gonna walk away.
I'll be back in a second.
What?
I really think we should stop seeing each other.
Thomas.
- Why?
- Looks bad. now come on.
I was ending it with your father as well.
And not because I didn't care for him.
I actually really do.
I care for him very much but...
Now. Thomas. the thing is you... he proposed.
- What?
- And I said. "Yes."
- No. no. no. no. no...
- Please. I don't want us to be disruptive.
- So. stop...
- Dad is not gonna leave her.
I'm not gonna let that happen.
No. this is the best thing for everybody.
- For who?
- For everybody.
Judith's going to be so much better off.
She won't be suffering anymore
under the weight of a dead marriage.
He's going through a crisis...
he's just going through a fucking crisis.
- That's all this is.
- Come on.
This doesn't have to be this difficult.
Please. everybody can win here.
God made a mistake when he made you beautiful.
Well. God's mistake is marrying your father.
Not yet. she isn't.
Look. can I just ask you one thing?
If any of this comes out.
who do you think is gonna get hurt?
It's not me.
It's not Ethan.
We both know how to land on our feet and it's not you.
You're so young.
This one person...
One person will be destroyed and we both know who that is.
What do you think is gonna happen?
You think that you can get married.
you think you can have the obligatory second family
and live happily ever after in your dream world?
- You thin...
- Well. obviously that can't happen.
What's that supposed to mean?
What's that supposed to mean? What is it supposed to mean?
Stop it.
- Stop it. Thomas. come on.
- I'm gonna tell him everything.
Thomas.
Thomas?
Thomas. what are you doing?
It's raining.
Okay.
I...
I broke up with Nick...
Because I got into Croatia...
And I want you to come with me.
I slept with Johanna.
No.
You're not like that.
And I thought that I was in love with her.
You're good?
No. Mimi. I'm not good.
Mimi?
I'm sorry.
You're just like them.
They won. Thomas.
God. they fucking bankrupted you.
- Hey.
- Thomas. did you spend last night here?
Yeah.
Well. that. was the best party
that Kenta has thrown in years.
Everybody was drunk and not just our alcoholic friends
but everybody.
Why did you spend the night?
I don't know. I just...
wanted to come home.
Are you upset?
Tell me about it.
What?
Is it about a girl?
And I am your mother. so?
Things have gotten messy and...
I wanna bail.
But I can't.
Then you know.
The only way out...
is through.
Right?
Where's dad?
He left early.
He said he had to go to the office and get some files.
He seems to have gotten over. what it...
Thomas?
- Dad?
- Thomas.
We need to talk.
- There are somethings that you don't know.
- Thomas. don't.
- Don't.
- That you need to know.
Johanna.
You two know each other?
Yeah.
What?
Well Ethan the thing is. is that...
He followed me.
You followed her?
That's not all I did.
I'm sorry. I...
I don't understand.
We slept together.
And not just once.
What?
You slick little shit. You have... I did right by you.
You have no idea. You have no idea.
I deserve you.
I'm sorry.
We're all sorry. Thomas.
I really do love him.
And he did right by you.
More than you know.
Good bye. Thomas.
Did you finish it?
I did.
Tell me about it.
Tell me about the only living boy in New York.
Aah. well...
It's about great people. artists.
Great friends.
One of them is a beautiful...
young girl. The other two.
one artist has talent. the other doesn't.
No. no matter how hard he tries.
no matter how badly he wants it. he just...
- I wasn't kissed by God in that way.
- But he has the girl.
Yes. And they're married.
And they plan to start a family.
Only. they have a little problem.
He's infertile.
And he asked a talented friend for help.
Yeah. you have a knack for a story. Thomas.
I get it from my father.
So...
they're artists and they don't want to use in vitro.
So. they go to a cheap bottle of cabernet...
Some Quaaludes and Simon and Garfunkel record.
- The pair of them decide...
- And... and... the husband's okay with that?
Well. look... they wanna use somebody that they know.
somebody that they love.
And of course. the artist with the talent. he's flattered.
and of course he agrees.
And he and...
the beautiful girl...
they...
they walk the city streets that night... for hours.
They're both so damn nervous.
And they end up at Washington Square Park.
where they dance...
to no music.
And the rest comes easy.
And does he love her?
He does.
In that moment he realizes he does...
And so it turns out that...
that the beautiful girl...
she gives birth to a wonderful son
and... her husband. gives up art.
becomes a very successful art dealer.
And the other artist?
He watches the boy grow from afar. You know?
Sees his own talent alive in this child.
So desperately wants to connect with his son.
And tell him everything.
And future his talent. you know.
But of course he never does make contact.
Until?
Until he decides to make it all his next book.
It's okay.
Mom?
Thomas.
What did he tell you?
Everything.
You here looking for razors?
Empty pill bottles?
Sit down.
What do you know. Thomas?
I know...
I know why you carry so much guilt.
I know that I...
already forgive you.
I know you are in love with someone you
haven't seen in over twenty-five years.
And you go to Riverside Park everyday to read his books.
I know. I know and it's okay.
- Who told you?
- He did.
Julian. W.F.
Whatever you wanna call him.
Is he dying?
He's not dying.
- No?
- No. he's not dying.
He's fine. He's just...
I don't know. he's tired.
Think he's lonely.
It was my idea not to tell you. not Ethan's.
- You have to know that.
- Okay.
You were trying to protect me.
Yes and...
and I knew that if you found out.
he would come back into my life
and then everything would go to shit.
Well. everything went to shit on its own. so...
Yeah. I guess.
Is he old?
He's messy.
Yeah. he always was.
An unmade bed of a man.
I like that.
You should.
Your father wrote it.
We're closed.
I'm sorry. I thought I locked the door.
- Hey.
I'll be quick.
- I know what book I want.
- Sure.
What did you think?
Serviceable?
You lie to make me feel good.
The character that surprised me the most was the father.
Which one?
The one who didn't run away.
Whatever happened to Mimi?
She's still in Croatia.
She got a fellowship.
I don't think she's coming back.
Did you hear back from Viking?
Yeah. it was a pass.
I'm sorry.
You want me to make a few phone calls?
No.
I wanna start something new. I have...
I have an idea.
Well. that's good.
Are you still speaking to Johanna?
No.
- You lying to me?
- Yeah.
- How's your mother?
- She's good.
She quit smoking.
Started writing for ARTnews again.
- Well. that's good.
- Yeah.
She has a date tonight.
Good for her.
Truly.